Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Granger Tripp Papers, 1958-1984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Granger Tripp papers 1958-1984
J. Walter Thompson Company.
0.8 linear feet Extent: about 600 items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00756
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The papers of Granger Tripp were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company in 1987.
Biographical Note
1922, Sept. 20 Born in Mt. Kisco, NY.
1943 B.A. Union College; upon graduation he was sent to Yale University by the US Army to study the Italian military government.
1944 Spent his ETO duty as a radio operator in the infantry.
1945 Joined Radio Reports, Inc.. Became branch manager, sales manager and vice president of the organization.
1946 Married Kathleen Martin.
1953 Joined the J. Walter Thompson Company as a Radio-TV commercial writer.
1960 Appointed Vice President of the J. Walter Thompson Company.
1966 Appointed Creative Supervisor of the J. Walter Thompson Company.
1968 Appointed Senior Vice President of the J. Walter Thompson Company.
1984 Retired from the J. Walter Thompson Company.
1984-1991 Consultant to the J. Walter Thompson Company and Ford Motor Company.
1991, March 20 Died, Mt. Kisco, NY.
Collection Overview
The Papers of Granger Tripp span the years 1958-1984. They chiefly consist of presentations and speeches, but also include correspondence, memoranda, publications, and clippings, as well as a manuscript score for the Kodak song The Times of Your Life, photographs, and audiovisual material.
The collection mainly reflects Granger Tripp's role as creative supervisor directing the creative work at the J. Walter Thompson Company between 1966 and 1984. It document's the contents and strategies of creative advertisement for the Eastman Kodak Company, as well as advertisement strategy and philosophy of the J. Walter Thompson Company in general. In addition to writings by Granger Tripp, the collection contains various writings, correspondence and memoranda of other members of the J. Walter Thompson Company creative team, including Jeremy Bullmore, Burt Manning, Douglass C. Harvey, Sonja Suspeh, Don Johnston and Joel Baumwoll.
Covering material that is client-specific as well as general in nature, the Granger Tripp collection consists of one large series referring explicitly to the collaboration between JWT and the Eastman Kodak Company and three additional series referring to the creative work of JWT in general. The Eastman Kodak Series documents the development, execution and public reaction to various creative advertising campaigns developed by the J. Walter Thompson Company for the Eastman Kodak Company. A Speeches And Writings Series refers to the company's strategies and philosophy in general. A small Publication Series contains publications on commercials for Eastman Kodak as well as advertising in general. An Audiovisual Series documents Granger Tripp's late affiliation with the Ford Motor Company. It consists of one u-matic video tape on the development of the Ford Taurus, 1986.
Subject Headings
Eastman Kodak Company; J. Walter Thompson Company; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising -- Management; Advertising executives; Advertising campaigns; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
If not noted otherwise, the speeches and writings are by Granger Tripp.
- Eastman Kodak Series
  - Subject Files: Kodak Songs
    - The Times of Your Life (includes a manuscript score) 1974-1978. (Box 1)
    - Turn Around Letters, Photos, and clippings, 1961-1965. (Box 1)
    - Memories; on the making of the TV-commercial, 1973-1974. (Box 1)
    - Kodak Centennial Record Album-Liner Notes 1979. (Box 1)
  - Subject Files: Instamatic Cameras
    - Case History, 1963-1972. (Box 1)
    - Naming; Tripp-Presentation; Frankfurt, Sept. 10, 1976. (Box 1)
    - Working copy, agency presentation to Kodak on naming the Kodak pocket instamatic cameras; (1972?). (Box 1)
    - Working copy and notes, a second agency presentation to Kodak on naming the Kodak pocket Instamatic cameras; (197?) (Box 1)
  - Subject Files: New Product Naming
    - Instant Camera, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Ektaprint Copier, 1974. (Box 1)
    - Additions to the Instamatic Camera line, 1974. (Box 1)
    - Additional Instamatic Cameras, 1976-1979. (Box 1)
  - Subject Files: International Organization
    - International Support of the Eastman Kodak Account, 1978-1979. (Box 1)
  - Speeches and Writings
    - The Kodak Corner Curl - background story of a long-standing trademark service, 196?. (Box 1)
    - What Works for Kodak Advertising - a presentation on the history of Kodak film advertising 1955-1980; June 14, 1982. (Box 1)
    - Emotion in Advertising - Presentation for Washington Ad Club; Jan. 24, 1984. (Box 1)
    - Kodak Film in a changing world - case history; Dec. 4, 1975. (Box 1)
    - Agency Presentation to Kodak European managers on coordination among various countries; Aug. 17, 1979. (Box 1)
    - Comment on Kodak Film Advertisement for 50th Anniversary issue of Advertising Age; Sept. 26, 1979. (Box 1)
    - Challenges for the photographic industry in the 80s - Keynote Address by Douglass C. Harvey, National Association of Photographic Manufactures; Nov. 5, 1981. (Box 2)
    - What is a Brand? - Presentation to Districts Sales Managers from the Kodak AAA and Latin American Districts; March 24- 26, 1980. (Box 2)
    - Stimulus and Response. Two presentations to the advertising technique developed at J. Walter Thompson, 1976and 1983. (Box 2)
  - Clippings
    - Clippings of publicity about the JWT/Kodak commercials, 1958-1975. (Box 2)
- Speeches and Writings Series
  - Awareness in Advertising. Two Presentations; June and September 1965 (Box 2)
  - What's new Pussycat? Presentation at Fall Training Conference on the influence in which advertising appears; Sept. 14, 1965. (Box 2)
  - A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Answer Print. Instructional talk to beginning tv commercial writers, 1967. (Box 2)
  - The Birth of an Idea. Speech by Jeremy Bullmore (no Date) (Box 2)
  - The Consumer has a mind as well as a stomach. Speech by Jeremy Bullmore; June 5, 1972. (Box 2)
  - Yes, but what response? Presentation by Burt Manning; Nov. 1978. (Box 2)
  - Crisis in Branding. Presentations by Sonja Suspeh, Don Johnston and Joel Baumwoll 1978-1982. (Box 2)
  - What Jim Young said - and what he didn't say. Speech by Jeremy Bullmore; July 1978. (Box 2)
  - Stimulus and Response. Presentation at Sao Paolo and Buenos Aires; Dec. 3-7, 1979. (Box 2)
  - What is a brand? March 13, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Presentation to Mr. Fujimori on Brand Loyalty; Aug. 29, 1983 (Box 2)
  - The JWT-Philosophy. Presentations for German Retail Advertisers and Kodak International Advertising Managers, 1980and 1983. (Box 2)
  - In Defense of the Press; Dec. 12, 1983. (Box 2)
- Publication Series
  - Advertising: Manipulation or Persuasion? by Al Achenbaum, 197? (Box 2)
  - Crisis in Branding. Publication of JWT/London, June 1978 (Box 2)
  - The Anatomy of a Television Commercial, 1970, Hastings House Publishers. (Box 2)
- Audiovisual Series
  - Taurus and the Pursuit of Excellence. Video, June 6, 1986. (Box 2)